Stanford University. >> Okay,
斯坦福大学
well welcome to lecture number three of Stanford CS193P.
欢迎来到斯坦福 CS193P 课程第三讲
This is spring quarter 2016. And today we
这是 2016 年春季
are going to mostly talk about the layer under the UI.
今天我们主要会介绍UI层
Okay, so we're gonna talk about Swift the language.
我们会讨论 Swift 这门语言
We're gonna talk about this foundation framework that
我们将会讨论位于核心服务层顶部的 foundation 框架
lives on top of Core services. So we're not going to be
所以我们不会讨论一整天非常多关于 UI 的内容
talking about the UI very much at all today. I do have a demo
我有一个用演示作为结束
towards the end. So I will finish off the slides and
我会完成这些幻灯片然后我们把这个演示做完
then we'll do the demo to finish. Okay, all right, so
好的
first thing I want to talk about is optional's,
首先我想介绍的是 optional
by the way, everything I am talking about today is
顺便说下 我今天介绍的所有东西
in your reading assignments. Okay, I'm just, the things I
都在你们的阅读作业里。好的
am talking about today I want to emphasize. I mean these
我想强调我今天介绍的东西
are things that you really really want to understand.
我的意思是这些东西你们真的真的需要理解
So if you see me mention it today and then you're reading
如果你在你的阅读作业里读到我今天提到的东西
it in the reading assignment, be sure to pay close attention
确保密切关注好吗？
all right? So as we learned in the last lecture,
那在我们上节课学的内容中
optional is just an enum, okay? It's a generic type kind
optional 就是一个 enum 是吧？它是一个有点像数组的泛型
of like array. It's got this little angle bracket T,
它有个小尖括号
which just means an Optional can be an Optional of any
这意味着 Optional 可以选择任何类型
type. And we know that to be the case. We can have
并且我们知道的情况
Optional strings or Optional even Optional optionals.
我们可以有可选字符串或者任何可选类型
We can have any kind of Optional we want. And so
我们可以选择任何我们想要的 Optional
it's an enum with two cases. The None case which is the not
所以这是一个有两种情况的 enum。
set case and then the Some case, which is the set case.
None 情况是没有设置东西，其它情况是设置了一些东西的
And in the Some case it has an associated value. And you
在一些情况下它有相关的值
learned all about enums last time. So this, syntax should
你们最近学过的关于枚举的内容
look completely, familiar to you. So let's look at some
所以这个语法对你们来说应该是完全熟悉的
of the little question mark, exclamation point stuff. And
让我们来看看这些小问号，惊叹号
what that means in terms of optional behind the scenes. So
在这些场景背后它们和 optional 的关系是什么
if you had a constant x which was of type optional string,
如果你有一个常量 x 它的类型是 optionl 字符串
right, string question mark.
对，字符串问号
And I set it to nil, then that's the same as saying that
然后我把它设置为 nil ，这等同于是说 x = Optional.None
x = Optional.None, right? Obviously, and same
对吗？显然， 的情况一样
thing if I had an optional string that was set to hello,
如果我有一个可选字符串设置成 hello
that'd be the same as x=Optional.Some
那就等于 x=Optional.Some
with the associated value, hello. Okay,
关联的值是 hello。 好的
everybody cool with that? And similarly, if I unwrap,
大家都觉得这很酷吧？类似的，假如我拆包
if I said, var y=x unwrapped, that just means switch x,
如果我说，var y=x 拆包，那就意味着开关 x
because we know that the way we unwrap Optionals and
因为我们知道我们那样子拆包 Optionals
get their associated value is with switch, so
所以我会打开 x 并用开关得到相关的值
I'm gonna switch on x. And in the case of Some, I'm gonna
在一些情况下，我会用 let 值
do that let value thing so I can grab the associated value.
因为这样我可以抓取相关的值
And then I'm just gonna set y equal to that value.
然后我要设置 y 等于那个值
In the case None, I'm gonna crash.
在空的情况下，我的程序会 crash
I'm gonna raise an exception, okay, because that's what
我要提出一个列外
unwrapping an Optional that's not said is supposed to do,
因为拆包一个 Optional 不意味着它应该这么做
it's supposed to crash, okay? And of course, in the case
它应该让程序奔溃。
where I'm doing if let, then I'm just gonna switch on x,
如果我用 let 这么做，然后我去 switch x
and I'm, the case of .Some, I'm gonna grab that y, and
在 .Some 情况下我用 y 拿出 x 的值
then I'm just gonna put some code, whatever my code is in
然后就会执行我放在下面的代码
there, and if let to happen there. And in the case None,
然而在 None 的情况下
I just break out of the switch, I do nothing.
我会直接跳出 switch 什么都不做
Okay, sound good? All right, so that's Optionals.
听起来不错？ 这就是 Optionals
Hopefully Optional now should start feeling very,
希望现在开始对 Optional 的感觉好点了
very comfortable to you cuz, as you found out,
在这些 API 里面
it's everywhere in these, in the API. Now Optionals have
你会发现到处都有舒服的提示
some more syntax, okay. That question mark and exclamation
现在 Optionl 有更多的语法了。你看见的那些问号和感叹号
point stuff, as you're seeing, is just syntactic sugar.
都是语法糖
It's just to make the, your typing it in easier and
这是为了让你写起来更舒服并且更好看
look nicer. It has a little bit more syntactic sugar.
它还有更多的语法糖
One thing is that Optionals can be chained. Okay, so
比如 OPtional 可以是链式的
this is the case where, for example,
如同这个例子的情况
in our calculator, we have the display, and
在我吗的计算器例子里，我们有显示，
lets say we want to get the text out of the display. And
让我们把一些想要得到的文本显示出来
then we want to send another message like hash value which,
然后我们想传递一些信息，比如哈希值，
strings understand this message hash value,
这些消息哈希后的字符串
how would we do that? Well of course we would say,
我们该如何做呢？
if let label equal display to unwrap the display. And
我们会这样，如果让 label 等于 display 这样去拆包 display
they we would say if let text equal the labels text,
然后我们会让 text 等于 label 的 text
and unwrap that. Then we would say let x equal the text hash
拆包之后，我们在让 x 等于 text 哈希后的值
value, okay? So that is how we would unwrap it.
所以，这就是我们如何去拆包这些信息
Well there is a lot easy way to do it which is this,
当然还有很多更容的方法来做
you just say display?.text?.hashvalue,
你可以这样 display?.text?.hashvalue
okay? So if you use question marks when you're, not when
如果你在这个时候用 ？ 而不是在声明 optional 类型时使用
you're declaring the optional but when you're actually using
这基本上意味着
it, that basically means, try and unwrap this and
尝试去把它们拆包
if you can then use that value to go to the next thing.
拆包后的值是否可以让你去到下一部分
If you can't, just return nil from this whole expression.
如果不行，整个表达是就返回 nil
Okay, this whole display question mark,
这个 dispaly 后面所有的问号，
that typed question mark, that hash value,
那个 哈希 值
that whole expression will return nil if at any point
如果它们当中有任何一点在拆包的时候返回了 nil
any of these things that were changing unwrap turns out to
这整个表达式就会返回 nil
be nil. So, if the display is nil or if the display's text
所以，如果 display 是空的，或者 display 的 text 是空的
is nil then this whole thing is gonna be nil.
那这整个就会变成 nil
So you see let x equal up there? What type do you think
所以你看见让 x 等于它们
x is right there? >> [INAUDIBLE].
这里的 x 是什么类型的 [讨论]
>> Int, almost.
[大概是 Int]
Optional int, exactly. It has to be optional int, because
对，可选 int 类型
any of those things could fail and it would return nil.
因为任何其它东西都可能失败并返回 nil
So it has to be able to take nil. So
所以它可以是 nil 值
that would be an optional int, cuz hash value returns an int,
因为它可以返回一个 int 的哈希值，所以它是一个可选 int
okay. So you're definitely gonna wanna use this,
你肯定会想用这种链条一样的方式去编程
chaining, it really makes your code read beautifully, okay.
它真的让你的代码看起来漂亮了
And the starts make Optionals make a lot of sense why we use
当我们开始使用可选类型的时候会有很多场景去使用它们
them so much. Okay, but there's more.
好的，但是还有别的用法
Here's another Optional syntaxtiture which is ??
这里是 Optional 的另一种用法叫做 ？？
Okay, and this is basically providing a default value
它基本上是在 case 为 nil 的时候提供一个默认的值
in case something is nil. Okay, so let's add an optional
来添加一个可选字符串 s
string here s, okay. I could say if s is not nil,
我可以说，如果 s 不是空
then I'm gonna set my display to be s, okay.
然后我会把我的 display 设置成 s
So let's say I'm setting the display in my calculator, and
这意味我在我的计算器上设置了显示
I never want it to be nil. At worst, I want it to be just
而且我不想让它是空的，最差也得是个空格字符
a space character. Because you might have noticed,
因为你可能注意到了
some of you when you're doing your homework,
当你在做你的一些作业的时候
that if you put nil into a label,
如果你往 label 里面放了 nil
its size will go to zero. Okay,
它的尺寸会变成0
cuz there's no text in there to have a natural size for. So
因为没有文本它就不会有一个天生的尺寸
sometimes you might want to have a code like this where if
所以有时候你可能想要一些这样的代码
you want to put nothing in the display,
如果你往 display 里面放了空的东西
you put a space character, so at least there's something in
你就放一个空格字符，因为这样至少这里有东西让 label 有高度
there for it to have a height, okay? Otherwise your display
否则你设置成 nil 的话
would keep disappearing if you kept setting it to nil. So
你的 display 可能会消失
we can do this, if s does not equal nil then display equals
那么我们可以这样，如果 s 不等于 nil 就让 display 等于 s
s, that should be s exclamation point right there,
用 != 表示不等于
otherwise display equals a space. Okay, well,
否则就 display 就等于一个空格
a much simpler way to put that is with this,
有一个更简单的方法
defaulting operator, which is to say the display.text
让 display.text = s
= s Okay? And that means if s is not nil then unwrap it and
这表示如果 s 不为空，就把它拆包
use that value, otherwise use space.
然后就使用拆包后的值，否则就使用空格
Got that? Everyone understand? I don't see any nodding heads
懂了吗？每个人都懂了吗？我没有看就有人点头
on that one. Make sense, okay? So this is, again, just
理解它，好吗？ 在说一遍
a simple way to have a default value in case an optional is
这是让 optional 在 nil 的情况下有一个默认值的简单的方法
nil. All right so let's talk about another thing, tuples.
继续介绍另一东西，元祖。
All right tuples are a type, okay? In Swift they're really,
元祖是一种类型，在 Swift 中它们非常酷
really cool. They're basically a way to build a type out of
它们是一种构建类型外的类型的基本方法
other types by grouping them, okay? And
好的
you can use it anywhere you can use a type, a tuple can be
你可以在任何地方用一个类型
used anywhere types are valid, okay? So, here's an example.
一个元祖在任何地方使用都是可以的，好的。这里有一个例子
I'm going to create x, okay? This let x, x is a constant.
我要生成一个 x 好的。这是 let x ，x 是一个常量
It's type is a tuple, with a string, int, and
这是一个元祖类型，含有 string, int, 和 double
double. So, even though tuple has the sound, to, in it,
尽管元祖听起来有 two 的声音
it's just not two things. Any number of things can be in
但并不是他有只有两个东西。一个元祖里面可以有任何数量的东西
a tuple okay? So x there is a tuple with string int and
好的，所以 x 是一个含有 string int double 的元祖
double. And I'm even setting it to a value,
我甚至可以往里面设置值
which is just parenthesis, a string, an int, and a double,
用括号包起来一个 string 一个 int 和一个 double
okay? Now how do I get those values out of the tuple?
好的。现在我该如何从这个元祖里面获得值呢
Well there is two ways to do it.
嗯。有两种方法
One is to say, let and then three, identifiers. These
一种，分配三个身份
are basically three local variable names, equals x,
它们是基于三个本地变量来命名的，等于 x
okay? And that's gonna extract the three values and put them,
好的，然后会取出三个值并保存到它们里面去
assign them to word, number, and value, which are gonna
分别放在 word，number，和 value 里
be local variables in this context, okay? Now, if you
它们会在这个上下文里得到蹦迪变量。好的，现在
tried to say let word, comma, number, closed parentheses,
如果你尝试 let (word, number) = x
equal x, the compiler will complain, because word, comma,
编译器是会出错的
number can't match a string in double tuples. Okay? So
应为 word, number 无法和元祖里的 double 关键字匹配。好的
this particular syntax is just putting names on the things in
这一部分的语法就是把这些东西放到这些命名里面
the Tuple so you can use them, so now you can print them out.
你可以这样使用元祖，所以你现在可以把它们打印出来了
Print word. Print number. Print value.
打印 word。打印 number。打印 value。
Value would be of type string. Number would be of type int
word 会是 string 类型，Number 会是 int 类型
and value would be of type double. Okay,
还有 value 会是 double 类型，好的
another way to do it is when you create the tuple, okay,
另一种这么做的方法是，当你在生成元祖时，好的。
you can name each of the things in the tuple. So
你可以为元祖里的每个东西命名。
here I'm letting x, this time be w: String i: Int v: Double.
这里我对 x 的 string 命名为 w，Int 命名为 i，Double 为 v
I'm giving the names w, i and v to the things inside
我在元祖里面分别起了几个名字叫 w，i 和 v
the tuple. I'm still assigning it, just like I did in
我继续给它赋值，就好像我在之前做的一样
the version above. But now if I want to get at the values,
但是现在，如果我想要得到一个值
I can just say x.w, x.i, and x.v to get at the tuple
我可以直接说 x.w，x.i，还有 x.v 来获得元祖中的值
values. See the difference between those two cases?
看出这两种方法的不同之处了吗?
One, you're kind of naming it when you declare the tuple,
一种，在你声明元祖的时候定义一种命名
the other one is you're taking a tuple that you got and
另一种是你拿到一个元祖
you're just extracting the values. And you can mix them.
然后你就取出值。并且你可以混合使用它们
For example I could say let = x.
比如我可以说 let = x
Even though I defined it x to have w, i and v,
尽管我给 x 定义了 w, i 和 v
I could ignore the w, i and v and instead just do
我可以忽略它们
the syntax from the top okay and call it wrd, num and val.
用 word， number 和 value 执行上面那种语法
Okay? So, tuples are cool because you can return
好的。所以，tuple 是很酷的
multiple values from a function with a tuple. Okay?
因为你可以从一个 function 中返回一个有多个值的 tuple
So, we know that returned values are arrow and a type.
所以，我们知道返回的值指向一个类型
Well, since a tuple can be a type, you can go arrow and
好的，当 tuple 可以是一种类型的时候
a tuple, and return values. Yeah?
你可以去指向这个类型，并返回它们的值，对吗？
>> Can you ignore some of
[学生提问]
the values? >> So, question,
所以，问题是
can you ignore some of the values?
你可以屏蔽这些值中的一部分吗？
Absolutely you can, if you use under bar. Underbar and
显然是可以的，你可以使用 underbar
swift is the universal I'm ignoring this character, okay,
swift 里的 underbar 是普遍的，在这一章我先不讲，好的
so you can put underbar in there. So yeah, so
所以你可以把值放在这里，
here I'm returning this tuple weight and
返回一个有宽度和高度的 tuple
height, obviously straight forward how we do that.
显然我们可以直接坐到
So tuples are perfectly valid return values, okay? So
所以 tuople 用来返回值是非常有效的，好的。
you can return multiple things from functions. All right,
所以你可以从这可方法返回多个值
range. So range is quite important, actually,
好的，range 。 range 在 Swift 里是非常重要的
in Swift. It's essentially just two end points,
它基本上就是两个结束点
okay, of anything that can be representative consecutively,
好的，它可以代表任何连续的东西
okay? So range, the type, is generic, like array,
所以，range ，这种类型是普通的，就好像数组
so you can have a range of ints. You can have
所以你可以有一个 int 的 range。
a range of indexes into something or whatever it
你可以有一个莫些东西内部的索引范围
really conceptually just has two things, a startIndex and
或者其它只要有两个东西的连续的东西。有一个起始索引和一个结束索引
a last index, okay, endIndex. An array's range, okay.
一个数组的 range，好的
If you wanted to get an array, arrange into an array,
如果你想要得到一个数组中部分范围的数组
it would be a range of ints,
可以用一个 int 型的 range
because an array is indexed by ints.
因为数组的索引是根据 int 来的
So you would have a range of ints. In fact you know,
所以你应该有一个 int 的 range。
you, there are methods in array where you can say, give
实际上你知道，在 array 里你可以调用一些方法
me this range of yourself, and you specify it as a Range.
提供它们你要指定的范围
A string's range is not Int. Okay, if you wanna substring,
一个字符串的范围不是 Int。 好的，若果你想要子字符串
you cannot use a range of Int. It's actually a range of
你不能使用 Int 的 range。它实际上是一个 String.Index 的range
String.Index, which is a different type than Int. And
它有着和 Int 不同的类型
you're gonna need to read all about that in the assignment,
而且你都会在你的作业里读到这些的
okay? One of the section's in assignment is
好的，作业里面面有一章讲的是
indexing into arrays in the ring assignment.
环形数组中的索引
And you're gonna wanna understand that, okay?
你们要去理解那个，好吗
It's a little bit complicated. I'm not gonna spend
这有一点点复杂。我不能花太多课上的时间
lecture time but just I'm pointing it out to you,
但是我会为你们指出它来
so you could go look at it. Okay? Now, there's special,
所以你们可以去看看，好吗？现在
just like with optionals we've got question marks and
有点特殊，想好像 optional 的问号和叹号
exclamation points. There's some special syntax for
range 有一些特殊的语法
ranges, okay, which is this ...and ..<.
比如 ... 和 ..<
You see them right here? Okay the... ..<!--? Okay?
你们可以看到吧 ... 和 ..<
This means a range right here, okay, that goes from 2 to 3.
这在这里表示一个 range，那个是从 2 到 3
This is a range that goes from 2 to 3 but does not include 3.
这是从 2 到 3 但不包含三
Okay? So that would be just the number 2, right there.
好的，所以那里讲会有两个数字
Okay? Now, see this 4 right here?
好的，现在，看这第四行
4 loops in swift all are 4 in like this.
Swift 中的循环都可以向第四行这样
So if you wanted to go for I equals 1, 2, 10 I plus plus or
如果你想要从 1 加到 2 加到 10 或者加到任何你想要的数值
whatever you would so that with these, ranges like this,
你就可以这样使用 range
okay, for IN 27 to 104 or whatever. Okay? And
好的，总 27 遍历到 104 或者任何其他范围。好的
you can make ranges that are more powerful than just direct
比起直接使用 range 你可以用更有力的方法起使用 range
ranges. I can't talk about that really on time wise, but
我不能花太多时间讨论这个
again check the documentation and
但是在次检查文档的时候你会看到 range 的超出
you'll see out of the ranges, okay? So that's when you see
所以，到那时你就会看到了
that. Okay, let's talk about data structures in Swift.
好的，来谈一谈 Swift 中的结构体
I'm talking about classes, structures and enums.
我讨论类，结构体，和枚举
Okay, you've already seen them in the example. I'm gonna
好的，你们已经在例子里看到它们了
talk about the similarities and the differences.
谈一谈它们的相同和不同
So what's similar between class, struct and enum,
所以，在 class，struct 和 enum 之间有什么相似之处呢
they're declared the same way, right? Just a keyword,
它们都用相同的方式声明对吧。
the name of the thing and then curly braces.
就同这个东西的名字作为关键字，然后收起它们
They all serve like that way. They're also similar and
它们都提供类似的方法。
that they can also have properties and
它们也都可以有属性和方法
functions. Okay? So you can have functions on there,
所以你可以在这里有方法和属性
and you can have properties. Enums cannot have stored
Enum 不能保存属性
properties. Only structs and classes can have stored
只有结构体和类可以存储属性
properties but enums can have computer properties. Okay?
但是枚举可以计算属性
The storage of an enum remember is the cases.
enum 存储的是 case
It's a discrete value thing so it's the cases and
所以它的 case 和它们的相关值
their associated values that's the storage.
是分开存储的
All right they all can have initializers.
当然它们都可以初始化
Okay, we haven't talked much about initializers yet.
好的，我们还没讨论很多关于初始化的东西
We're gonna get that today. Eh, so they're all allowed
我们今天会来说一说。额
to have initializers except enum. Okay,
所以它们除了 enum 都可以初始化
obviously enum doesn't need an initializer because you just
显然 enum 不需要初始化
set it to the discrete value with its associated values.
应为你是是设置了一些离散的值和它们相关的值
Okay? All right. Differences. One, inheritance. Okay?
好的。当然，不同之处，继承。对吗
With classes, you can inherit, structs and enum you can't.
在类中，你可以继承，结构体和枚举不行
Value types, I talked about this before, okay? Structs and
我在这之前介绍过值的类型
enum are value types. They're passed around by value.
结构体和枚举是值的类型。它们通过值来传递
Class is a reference type. You pass pointers to it around. It
类是一种引用类型。通过指针来传递
lives in the heap. Okay? Let's talk a little more about value
它们保存在堆中。好的，来讨论更多关于值和引用
versus reference. Value means that it's copied when passed
值意味着当它作为参数传递个方法是它是个拷贝
as argument to a function, that's kind of obvious. But
这是显而易见的
it also copies when you assign it to another variable.
当你把他分配个另一个变量时它也会拷贝
If I say varx=y if y is a value type,
如果我说 var x = y 如果 y 是一个值类型
x will be a copy of y.
x 会是一个 y 的拷贝
A copy, so if y is an array y might be an array. Okay? And
所以如果 y 是一个 array
you say, x equals y. And then you say, x append this thing,
然后你说 x = y 接着用 x 拼接一些东西
that thing will not be appended to y. Because x
这些东西不会被拼接到 y 上去
was a copy of y. You see what I'm talking about there? Okay.
应为 x 是 y 的一个拷贝。你们明白我在说什么吗？好的
So that's a big difference with value semantics.
所以这是它们之间的一个特别大的不同
Even just assigning them, is a copy of them. A value symantec
甚至个它们赋值也是对它们的拷贝
thing is immutable if it's signed to a let variable.
一个用 let 分配的值是不可变的
Okay? So if you have an array okay,
如果你有一个数组
since that value symmentic cuz an array is a struct.
因为 array 是一个 strut
If you assigned to a let, let x equal an array you cannot
如果你给一个 let 赋值， let x 等于一个数组
append things on to that array cuz it is immutable. Okay,
那你就不能往这个数组上面拼接东西，因为 x 是不可变的
same thing with the dictionary or whatever. Okay. Remember
dictrionary 或者其它东西在这一点上也是相同的
the function parameters. All of them are constants so
记住那些方法的参数，它们都是常量
of course you'd copy them into there, you can't modify them.
所以你得把它们拷贝进来，你不能修改它们
Because of the way copy symmentics work, Swift makes
由于 copy 的工作方式
you when you do have a struct or enum you have to mark all
Swift 会让你在那些 struct 或者 enum 里面
functions that might change that thing. Mutating functions
把可能会改变的方法标记出来
with the keyword mutating. So like mutating func whatever.
用 mutating 关键子来表示可变方法。
Okay? If that function could change that struct.
如果那个方法可以改变他的结构体
And the reason for that is when Swift copies it
当 Swift 拷贝它的时候
it doesn't want to actually make a copy. Okay?
它实际上是不会制作一个备份的
It gets another pointer to it but as soon as you try to
在你视图去改变它的时候
mutate it then it's gonna have to copy it. You see? So
会用一个指正指向它并拷贝这个指针
it's kind of a performance enhancement. So
所以这是一种增强的执行方式
any time you have a struct that has a function that
一旦你的结构体里的方法改变了它的值
changes the values, any of the values of the struct,
这结构体里的任何一个值
you have to put mutating in front so Swift knows
你必须在 Swift 知道你这么做之前将它变为可变的
that you're doing that. Okay, reference types, okay.
好的，参考类型
This is what you're used to,
可能这就是你所用到的
probably. Things are stored in the heap.
东西存放在了堆里
You have a reference to them. Those references are counted
你有一个他们的引用，那些引用会被自动计数
automatically. That means there's no garbage collection
这意味着在 Swift 中是没有垃圾回收机制的
in Swift. All right, there's no mark and sweep in
当然，它们没有标记的时候回从堆里面被清除
the heap. Every single time you create a new pointer to
每当你创建一个新的指针指向堆里的某个东西时
something in the heap Swift keeps track of that and
Swift 会把这个痕迹保存下来增加一个计数值
it keeps incrementing a count. And when that count goes down
然后当计数值成为零的时候
to zero because maybe the last pointer that's pointing to it
可能是最后一个指针不在指向它了
goes out of scope or maybe you assign that last pointer to
或者这最后的指针指向了其它什么东西
point to something else. Nothing points to it.
这块内存不在被指向的时候
It immediately removes that from the heap.
它会立马从堆里面被删除
Okay, predictably removed from the heap immediately.
好的，可以预见会很快的从堆里面移除
So, it's very different than garbage collection, where
所以，这和垃圾回收机制非常不同
garbage collection is kind of going on in the background,
垃圾回收是一种在后台运行
and it might collect a whole bunch from the heap,
一次性手机一整串堆里的东西
all at once. That's been sitting around for a while.
那会等上一段时间
This is predictable,
这是可以预测的
memory management and it's all managed for you. Okay,
这是你可以管理的内存管理
there's only one way that you participate in that, which is
你要参与其中只有一种方法
the weak and strong, which I'll be talking about later,
使用 weak 和 strong。我过会向你们解释
okay? Let's see, constant pointers.
好的，来看指针常量
Okay, if you have a constant pointer to a class,
如果你在一个类里有一个指针常量
obviously it's a pointer, so you're still mutating it,
显然这是一个指针，所以你依然能修改它
right? It's not like a struct where if I say var y = x and
对吗？ 这不像我说的 var y = x 的那种结构
then I add something to y, it doesn't modify x.
当我想要给 y 加点什么的时候，这并不会修改 x
If I say var y = x and they're classes, then if I send
若果我说 var y = x 而且它们都是类
a message to y, it's sending a message to x because they're
然后如果我想 y 发送消息，这会个 x 发送一个消息，因为它们是同一个东西
the same thing. Right they, that same thing lives in
同一个在堆里保存的东西
the heat. There's no copying, so let, all let means is that
没有拷贝，所以 let
pointer's not going to change. It doesn't
所有的 let 意味着那个指针是无法被修改的
mean what the pointer points to won't change.
这不意味着指针指向的东西无法被修改
Okay obviously so when you pass a pointer to a class
显然，当你把指针当做一个参数传递给类的时候
as an argument, then it does not make a copy, it's just
它不会产生一个拷贝
passing a pointer. Okay. Now how do you know which to use?
它就传递了一个指针。好的，现在你知道该怎么用了吗？
Struct versus class, specially.
特别的，结构和类
Okay, enum is pretty obvious. But struct versus class well.
enum 是很明显的。除了结构和类
Usually you're gonna choose class over struct.
通常你会在类和结构中选一个
Okay. Because this is object oriented program.
因为这是面向对象编程
You use to do it and that's going to be fine.
你这样使用会更好一点
Struct is gonna be used for more fundamental types.
Struct 更多被用作基础类型
Okay, things like strings and doubles, and ints and arrays
向是 string 和 double ， int 和 array 在 diction 里
in dictionaries, and also for drawing, points, rectangles.
也会为了绘图有点，矩形
Do you see what I'm saying, smaller things that
你知道我在时候什么，一个更小的独立的东西
are self-contained, that it makes sense to copy by value.
用在需要复制值的场景上
You want the value semantic, that's gonna be your primary
你要这值的语言。当你在传递这值的时候
reason for choosing struct as you want values
你想要这些值的语义
semantics when you're passing this thing around. Otherwise,
会成为你选在 struct 的主要原因
you're gonna choose classes, okay? Anything big is almost
否则你就选类
certainly gonna use the class, all right? Okay.
任何大型的东西坑定会使用类，对吗？
On the methods. So now we are gonna talk about the syntax
好的。这这些方法里，我们要来说说这些方法的语法
of methods. Okay, I showed you this in class a little bit but
在这个类里我会展示一点
I'm gonna talk about the full semantics here of it.
我还会介绍它在这里的完整的语义
So interesting about the naming of functions, so
这些方法的命名挺有趣的
here is someone defining a method and here is someone
这里定义了一个方法
calling this method. Okay? Okay, so watch this colored
这里调用了这个方法。好的？好，在我讨论这几种东西的时候
stuff going on as I talk about these various things going on.
注意这些高亮的部分
So all parameters to functions have an internal name and
所有方法的参数都有一个内部的名字和一个外部的名字
an external name, every single parameter.
是每一个参数都有
So here's the first parameter, here's the second parameter,
那么这里是第一个参数，这里是第二个参数
they both have an external name and an internal name.
它们都有一个外部的名字和一个内部的名字
Okay? The external name comes first. Internal name comes
好的。先说外部名字，在说内部名字
second. The internal name is the name of the local
内部名字是在你的方法里面的本地变量的命名
variable that's gonna be used inside your method.
All right? So that's this one right here,
所以这就是内部命名
internal name. Shows up right before the colon. Okay?
就是出现在这冒号之前的东西
First and second. You can see how first and
第一个和第二个
second are the names I used for those inside my function.
你可以看到在我的方法里我是如何给第一个和第二个起名的
Don't appear anywhere here. Notice first and
不要出现在别的地方。
second do not appear in the funk bar call. Okay,
注意第一个和第二够不在方法块后面出现
cuz those are the internal names. The external name
因为它们是内部的名字
is what the caller uses when they call this method. Okay,
当这个方法被调用的时候这个方法会被使用
so you can see bar down there. It says externalFirst: 123,
你可以看到这里有个下划线。这表示 外部第一个参数：123，
externalSecond: 5.5, right? Okay, it's using the external
外部第二参数：5.5，好的
names first and second never appear but
第一个和第二个名字并没有出现
first and second are still used in the implementation,
但它们仍然能够被实现别使用
those in the internal names. Okay,
可以在方法里用它们的内部名字
you can put an under bar if you don't want callers
如果你不想让你的传递参数使用外部的名字
to use an external name at all for a given parameter. Okay,
你可以使用 _ 来替代它们
so if you put underbar as the external name then there will
所以你要是在外部名字的地方放了一个 _ 那这里有不会有外部参数
be no external parameters. So you see it says foo(123), not
比如你调用 foo(123)
foo(externalFirst or anything, it's just nothing, 123. And
不用调用 foo(外部第一个参数名或者其它什么东西，什么都不用，就写123
in fact, this is the default for the first parameter.
实际上，第一个参数默认就是这么做的
The first parameter defaults to under bar, you don't need
第一个参数默认就是 _
to put an under bar there when you're creating a function.
当你创建一个方法的时候你不需要再在那里放 _
Just by default an under bar would be put there for you,
那里默认就为你放了一个 _
okay? Now you could specify an external name for the first,
现在你指定第一个外部参数的名字，这是合法的
it's legal. Okay, I'll show you that in a second. But
我会展示第二个怎么做
by default under bar is the external name for the first
默认的 _ 只有第一个外部命名才有
parameter only. All the other ones. Okay? The default is
那么所有其它的是什么呢？
the internal name. So, if you don't have an external name,
它们默认都是内部名字。所以如果你不想要一个外部名字
then it defaults to being the internal name. Got it?
它们默认会是一个内部的名字。明白了吗？
Okay. Any parameter's external name can be changed, okay?
好的。任何参数的外部名字都是可以修改的
You can change even the second one to be underbar, so
你甚至可以把第二个改成 _
that the second one has no name, okay?
这样第二个就没有名字了，对吗？
But don't do this, okay? It's very anti Swift
当时不要这样做，好吗？
to either remove the second parameter name or
把第二个参数移除或者添加到第一个参数，是很反 Swift 的
to add it back to the first. Adding to the first is
添加到第一个可能不是很反 Swift
probably less anti Swift, there is probably some case
可能在某些场景里会需要这么做
where that might actually make some sense. Removing them for
但是后面要把它们删掉也是非常麻烦的
subsequent ones is probably really bad. Okay,
I don't think I've ever had to do that in my entire life of
在我用 Swift 写程序的时候，我不记得我曾经这么做过
writing swift so.
All right now, methods are obviously overriddeable,
现在，方法是可以被覆盖的
this is object orientated programming. Right and the way
因为这是面向对象编程
you do it, you just put the word override in front of
你只需要在 func 或者 var 前面加 override 关键字
the func or var. Both properties and functions can
属性和方法都是可以被覆盖的
be overridden right, so you put override in there. It is
所以你把 override 放在这里
possible to mark a method or a property final in which case
它可以在子类的情况里用来标记方法和属性
no one can subclasses. Okay, there won't be a list,
一个子类不能再类前放 override
a subclass can't say override that thing. The compiler won't
编译器不允许这么做
let them. Okay, you can also mark an entire class final,
你也可以在类的最后标记一个入口
and then the whole thing is not subclassable. All right?
然后整个类就不能有子类了
Now, both types and instances can have methods and
现在类和对象都可以有方法和属性
properties. What does that mean? So, so
这意味着什么呢
far in all the demos we've done,
现在我们已经完成了所有的演示
all you've seen is instance methods and
你看到的都是对象方法和对象属性
instance properties. In other words,
换言之
they are properties that you get from an instance of
它们是你从一个对象中拿出来的属性
the thing. Okay, an instance of the calculator brain.
好的，一个计算器大脑的对象
Someone actually created a calculator brain in the heap
实际上你已经在堆里创建了一个计算器的大脑并且给它发送消息
and you send it messages, okay. Those are instances
那些事对象消息
messages, Instances methods and instances properties. But
对象方法和对象属性
it is possible to have methods and
然而在它的类里它还能有自己的方法和属性
properties on the type itself, so calculator brain,
所以在计算器大脑这个类里面它可以有方法，对吗
the type can have functions, okay? And here's what
这里是调用他们时的样子
it looks like to call them. So here I have a little example.
我这里有一个小例子
Here I have a var d which is a double, okay?
我这里有有一个 double 的变量 b
And it's set to some value. So this d is an instance of
然和我给它设置一些值，所以这个 d 是一个 double 的实例
a double. It is an actual double that has some value,
这个 double 实际上有一些值
all right? And here I'm checking by sending a message,
我通过发送一个消息来检查这一点
an instance method right here. Or probably a property
它是一个对象的方法，也可能是一个属性
actually. Instance property on D, where I'm asking
对象的 D 属性如果是负数的
if it's signed is the minus sign, I'm just making this up,
我就把他变成正数
there's probably not even such a method on double.
在 double 里面可能没有这样一个方法
But that would be an instance property or method and
我会向 D 的属性或对象发送消息
I would be sending it to D,
which is an instance. If it does have a minus sign,
如果它没有负号
I'm going to use a type property. Or type function,
我会使用一个类属性
rather, of double here, to change its probably absolute
或者在 double 里的这个类方法里会把它变成绝对值
value, so it'd probably change its sign there. Okay.
所以我可能在这里改变它的符号
Notice the syntax here, Double.abs, okay.
好的。注意这里的语法 Double.abs
This is the name of the function abs, okay, and
这个方法的名字叫 abs
I'm accessing it by saying Double. So in other words, I'm
然后我通过向 Double 发消息来访问它
putting the name of the class. Not an instance of a class,
换句话说，我把这个类名放在这里。不是一个类的对象
not a variable of that class, but the actual name of
也不是一个类的变量，而是一个类的名字
the class, dot abs. Okay, that's it's gonna be defined,
.abs 好的。那个 abs 会被定义
that abs, will be defined like this. Static func abs.
会用这种方法定义 Static func abs
This would be in the class double. And you put this word
这会在 double 类的里面
static and that says that you don't send this to double
在这里放关键字 static 意味着你不会把它发送给 double 对象
instances. You send it to the Double class by saying capital
你会用大写的 D ，Double 点，发送给 Double 这个类
D Double dot. Okay? Why do we have these things? Okay these
为什么我们会有这些东西？
are usually utility functions kind of global functions but
我们经常会需要一些全局的功能函数
they're really strongly associated with the class. So
但是他们和这些类有很强的关联的
we put them as class methods, okay?
所以我们把他们放到类方法里面，好吗？
That's what they're for, mostly. Maybe you have a class
这是它们存在的主要原因
method that creates Shared instances of a class, okay.
或许你会有个类方法来创建一个类的共享对象
Something like that, we'll see a few of these.
像这样，我们会看到这些
Once you start to see them in action,
一旦你在实践中看见他们
you'll start to understand. But I just wanna make sure you
你就会明白的。
understand that there is a difference between these two
但是我想确保你们理解这两者之间是不同的
and this static that makes a difference on declaration,
这个 static 在声明的时候是不同的
okay. That's also in the reading assignment, make sure
好的。那些也在阅读作业里面
you read that carefully. In the homework assignment,
确保你仔细的阅读过了
I even say be careful to read this carefully. All right,
在作业里面我甚至也说了仔细阅读
properties, okay. Properties are really cool.
好的。属性是很酷的
In Swift we're only just scratching the surface so
在 Swift 里我们才刚刚揭开它的表面远不及它所能做的
far of what they can do. But one really cool thing about
但是有一件关于它的很酷低是
them is that you can observe changes to a property, okay.
你可以观察一个属性的改变
And you need to do that by, here's your var, okay. This is
而且你需要这样做，这是你的变量。
a stored property, this is not a computed property,
这是存储的属性，这不是一个计算的属性而是用来存储的
it's stored, okay. It stores in ints, its value is 42. But
它存在 int 里，这个值是 42。
I'm putting the curly braces after it, not because I'm
我把大括号放在它的后面，我要去得到和设置它
gonna do get and set, I'm not computing it. But
我不去计算它
I'm gonna add willSet and/or didSet, okay. So willSet and
但是我会使用 willSet 和 didSet。好的
didSet, this is just code in here that's gonna get called
willSet 和 didSet，当调用 get 和 set 时就会调用者两个方法
whenever this thing gets set. Okay, before and after. Before
好的，在这之前或在这之后。
it gets set, after it's been set, okay. And inside there
这 get 之前和 set 之后，好的
newValue is going to be the value it's going to be set to
在设置到 willset 的时候 newValue 就是要设置的值
in willSet. And oldValue is this value it used to have in
当你执行 didSet， oldValue 就是已经存储着的值
did, when you're executing in didSet, okay. So, pretty cool.
好的，非常酷
And you can do that for stored properties, you can do it for
你可以这样来存储属性，你也可以对继承的属性这么做
inherited properties, properties you inherit even,
你甚至可以继承属性
okay. And you can do it for computed properties as well,
你也可以用它来计算属性
okay. Also here, this will be,
好的
one thing to note about this is these willSets and didSets,
这些 willSet 和 didSet 要注意的是
if you mutate a value type they will get called,
如果你改变一个值的类型 get 会被调用
okay. So, operations here from our calculator brain,
所以我们对计算器大脑的操作放在这里
dictionary string operation that is a value type,
字典字符串操作是一个值类型
dictionary is a value type, right. So
字典是一个值类型
if you add something to this dictionary,
所以如果你往字典里加了什么
this will get called. willSet and didSet will get called,
会调用 get。willSet 和 didSet 会被调用
okay. That's not true if it's a reference type, okay.
如果它是一个引用类型的话这么做是无效的
If that if this property isn't a class and
如果这属性不是类而且你修改了类的某个地方
you change the class somehow, it can't detect that, so
它是不会检测到的
it doesn't do willSet and didSet, okay.
所以它不会执行 willSet 和 didSet
You have to change the pointer itself. All right, okay.
你必须改变指针本身
One very common thing to do in these willSets and didSets is
通常 willSet 和 didiSet 的用途是更新 UI
update the UI. You got a method in your controller.
你在你的控制器里得到一个方法
You set some value in controller that changes
你改变了控制器某处的值就会在 UI 上显示出来
the way the UI would look. You ask your view to
你要求你的 View 重绘
draw itself again, okay. Very, very common.
好的。非常非常常见
We're gonna be doing that up the wazoo in the next lecture,
我们会在下一节使用它们
okay. All right. Lazy initialization. So, this is
好的。懒加载
a little bit of a cheat code of Swift right here.
这是 swift 种有点欺骗性的代码
You can declare vars to be lazily instantiated.
你可以声明一个懒加载的变量
Which means that, their value, this equals calculator brain,
这意味它们等于计算器的大脑实际上不会执行
will not actually happen. That assignment will not happen
知道有些地方需要调用它了才会执行分配
until someone asks for the brain, okay.
好的
If someone tries to send a message to this brain or
若果有什么动向想个这个大脑发一个信息
get a property to this brain,
或者从这个大脑里拿到一个信息
then it's gonna get initialized.
然后它就会被初始化
So in other words, it's lazily instantiated, okay.
换句话说，这就是懒加载
And you can do it like that, okay. Just lazy var brain,
而且你可以像这样做。就 lazy var brain
calculatorbrain. You can do down here, okay.
你可以在这里做
Lazy var myProperty = self.initializedMyProperty.
So, I'm calling a method on myself to initialize one of my
所以我告诉我自己去初始化我的一个属性
properties. Normally, this would be illegal
without the lazy. The reason this would be illegal
without the lazy is that you cannot send any messages to
yourself or access any of your properties until you're fully
initialized, okay. And this is part of your initialization,
so it's a catch 22, you can't do it. But
if you make this lazy, now you can. Because it's not actually
going to happen until after you're fully initialized and
someone comes along and tries to access myProperty, okay. No
one can access myProperty for your initialize anyway. So,
once you're fully initialized, I'm gonna access myProperty,
lazy, boom. This method will get called to initialize you,
got it? And how about this one in the middle here,
some property of this given type equals a closure
with open parentheses,
closed parentheses on the end. This just means,
initialize this by executing the code inside this closure,
okay. It's very similar to doing
self.initializeMyProperty but you're putting the code
in this closure instead of putting it in initialize
myProperty, whatever that method is, okay. Now,
normally inside here, okay. If this weren't lazy,
you would not be able to access self in here.
Because again, this is a part of initialization, you can't
do anything with self until you're fully initialized. So
if you tried to put self in here,
the compiler will complain. But if you make it lazy,
now you can access self in here. Got it?
Call your own methods or whatever you wanna do, okay.
So that's lazy. The reason this is kind of a cheat code
is that this lazy business satisfies the requirement
that all your vars have to be initialized, okay. So even
these, though these things are being initialized lazily,
they're still being initialized for
the purposes of that rule that all your vars have to be
initialized. This kind of will often keep you from having to
write an initializer. You won't need an init,
because of this lazily do it, okay.
That's why I say it's kind of a cheat code a little bit,
okay. One thing about lazy, they always have to be var.
So there's no such thing as lazy let, okay. Lazy var
only, okay. You can also use laziness to get around some
dependency issues, if you have one var depends on another. If
you can make one of them lazy, then that'll be fine, right.
Cuz the lazy one will call the one that gets pre-initialized,
okay. All right, let's talk about array.
Okay, I'm not gonna spend much time on this cuz array you're
used to array, you know what array is.
In other languages, it's pretty much the same in Swift.
So I'm just gonna try and cover the syntax a little bit.
One thing is we've been using this kind of syntax for
dictionary, right, dictionary angle, extreme colon
operation, remember that? This is the formal
syntax for an array but this square bracket,
string closed square bracket is more informal and
it's the one we use, okay. So as we go forward, we're gonna
use [string] to mean the type array of string, okay.
And similarly for dictionary, [key:value]. That is
dictionary with keys of this and values of that type, okay.
Now, this is the type,
so the open parenthesis close parenthesis on the end just
means that I'm calling the initializer with no arguments.
Same as up here. So don't get confused by that, okay.
So that just means I'm initializing,
I'm creating an instance of an array of string, okay. That's
what both of those mean. So, I can also create arrays and
initialize them by just saying some variable like animals
there which is constant let animals = [ list a bunch of
things ]. That creates an array of those things.
And notice I don't specify any type here.
Why, why do I get away with that? What does Swift do?
It infers type. So, we would look at this and say string,
string, string, string all right.
This is an array of string. Now if I went giraffe, cow,
three, bird, then Swift would complain, can't infer the type
of that array, because it's not all the same type.
Okay, so we'd infer it here. Now, notice this
animals.append("Ostrich"), if I put an Ostrich in here,
this will not compile, okay. Compiler will say no,
that's because animals is let, it's a constant.
So this is a constant array, it can not be modified.
If I put var right here, no problem, it would work, okay.
Now, if I say let animal = animals[5].
That's gonna crash my program. Array index out of bounds,
just like most Programming systems do. It's one
of the few cases that you can crash your program in Swift.
We know unwrapping optionals is one, this is another one.
If you array index out of bounds,
it will crash, okay? How do you enumerate array?
I wanna look at everything in an array. Yeah, I could do for
with a range 0.., the length of the array, right?
0.., less than sign, length of the array. But
that's not how you would do it, you would just say, for
animal in animals, okay? This is gonna loop through, and
this local variable is gonna be assigned each
of the animals, okay? That's how you enumerate an array.
All right, interesting Array methods.
Okay, I'm not gonna spend a lot of time on this slide.
But I really want you to understand that these methods
are here, okay, and you're gonna wanna use them.
They will really clean up your code.
They'll keep you from doing a lot of code, this like for
enumerate through my array, do this, if then, this then,
collect it in another array, all that kinda stuff you can
put in one liners, okay? So what do these things do?
These things use closures to operate on arrays. So filter,
okay, is a method in Array. You send it to it.
You provide a closure, which takes whatever type is in the,
in the array and returns a bool. And it just
executes that closure on every single element of the array,
and it includes the ones
where you return true from your closure. And it excludes
the ones you don't, until filter returns a new array,
which is only the things that match your closure, okay? So
here for example, let bigNumbers = this
array.filter, here's my closure,
$0 is this thing that's gonna be for each of these,
called on each of these. If $0 is greater than 20,
I'm gonna return true. So this returns an array, bigNumbers,
that only has 47 and 118, cuz those are the only
two things greater than 20, got it? Okay,
there's another one simpler, similar, which is map.
Map takes your closure and your closure converts each
element in the array to something else.
So if you had an array of ints and you wanted it
to be an array of strings, you could do it with this,
okay map, closure. Notice, by the way,
no parentheses here. You see, map, okay,
map takes an argument, which is a closure there. But I have
no parentheses after map around the curly braces like I
had up here with filter. I put this in here to show you that
those parentheses are optional when a closure
is the last argument to a function, okay?
When a closure is the last argument to the function,
it can be outside of the function's parentheses, okay,
and live on its own out here.
Okay, here's another function, okay, called reduce.
This reduces the array to a single result. Okay, so
this particular one, you can convince yourself of it later,
it adds up the numbers, okay. It just reduces,
starts with zero, and for each one it takes the amount so
far and adds it to the next thing in there, so
it adds up the numbers.
Notice this one has two arguments,
an initial and a closure. Okay, see this closure here,
an initial? And notice the closure also is still living
outside of the parentheses. The first argument is inside
the parentheses, but the closure is living outside.
This one had no first argument.
It only had the closure, so it has no parentheses here. This
one does, okay? This is called trailing closure syntax, and
you almost always wanna use it, it looks really cool,
reads really nicely. Okay, dictionary.
All right, so dictionary, similar to array,
it's just looking up keys and values.
Again, we're gonna use this more informal kind of syntax,
okay? [String:Int] means the type dictionary where
the strings are keys and ints are values, all right?
So if I have pac10teamRankings here, and
I had Stanford at number 1, Cal number 10, and I let the,
I guess it's Pac-12 now. I should update this,
should't I? So, okay, Cal 12 and so if I say here, let
ranking = pac10teamRankings ["Ohio State"],
that's obviously, no Ohio State in the Pac-12.
So the ranking here has to be an Int?, right, it's
an optional Int, we already saw that in our, calculator.
Okay, anytime you dereference a dictionary,
it's gonna return an optional of whatever type is
the dictionary's values are, okay? The way you enumerate
through a dictionary is using a tuple, okay, for (key,
value) in pac10teamRankings, inside here, key is
gonna be the key. And here is gonna be the value for each of
the things in the dictionary, okay? Pretty cool. And again,
you could put under bar here if you just wanted the keys,
or under bar here if you just wanted the values. All right,
String. String is a little complicated in Swift because
it's full Unicode.
And I mean full Unicode. All right so,
it supports all kinds of languages. Languages where
one character might be many, many different codes, okay.
So characters are no longer single codes anymore. Okay,
so, that's why, when you index into a string,
you're not indexing by ints. You're indexing by
indexes that know how to move along in a string past things
like emojis that might have multiple codes, okay?
So you're gonna wanna read about this, so
I'm not gonna cover it all in lecture here. But
one interesting way to look at a string is by calling
this, String.CharacterView, okay? If you call character
view on a string, you'll get the characters
in what looks like an array of character, okay? It looks like
an array of characters, not actually array of character.
It's a character view. But it can be indexed with ints,
okay, and you can get at the characters. So that's one way.
Another way, you can actually create an array,
one of the initializers that array will take is a string,
okay. And then it'll be an array of characters.
Okay, not quite as efficient as this character view, but
you could do it that way, especially with a long string,
you probably might not wanna do that. Okay, but that's
a little easier way to get at it, otherwise you have to
understand what it says in the reading about string indexes,
okay. String.index that class and
how to use it to get things out of a string,
okay? There are a lot of other cool methods in String,
though, like hasPrefix will tell you whether one string
has the prefix of another string. You can capitalize and
lowercase and uppercase these strings.
You can even do sophisticated things like,
get me all the components in this string separated by
this other string. So
this is a method you send to a string. This might be a comma,
let's say, and this, right here like this, and it will
extract all the strings that are separated by a comma.
Okay, kinda fun. So make sure you familiarize yourself with
a lot of the methods in String so that you don't waste your
time writing this method which already exists, okay, or
similar methods like it. All right, other classes that
are here that you have to think about. One is NSObject.
This is the base class of all Objective-C classes, okay.
Now, we know, in Swift, it doesn't have a mandatory base
class, like CalculatorBrain, no superclass, okay.
Perfectly legal in Swift. But
all Objective-C ones have to be subclasses of NSObject.
Now, there are some APIs, they're fairly rare and
I'll tell you which ones they are when we get to them later
in the quarter, that are Objective-C APIs, okay.
And when you use them in Swift,
you need to have a class that subclasses from NSObject. So
in Swift, it's perfectly legal to subclass from NSObject,
not required except for in these few cases I'm gonna talk
about later in the quarter. But legal and it really won't
hurt anything, so you could do it if you want. Some people
just get in the habit of always sub-classing for
NSObjects in Swift, if they're not sub-classing from
something else, because why not, okay. Then their classes
are always ready for whatever these weird old APIs are,
okay? NSNumber, okay in Objective-C,
there's no such things as well structs
in Objective-C are not like structs in Swift.
They're not this nice value type semantic thing.
Okay, structs are more like C structs okay, so double and
int, string, array,
dictionary. In Objective-C these are classes.
Okay, sorry, array and diction are classes.
Double and int are C-double and int. Not even objects,
okay? So that brings a problem in Objective-C,
what if I wanna put a bunch of numbers into an array? Okay,
you can't do it, because an array is an array of objects.
And doubles and ints are C primitive types,
in Objective-C. So this class NSNumber,
is how you wrap a primitive type into an object.
So you can put it in an array.
Now in Swift we don't need that, because in Swift arrays
and dictionaries will accept structs, and double and
int is a struct. Okay, so this NSNumber not necessary for
that, okay. Now there are iOS APIs that take,
for example, arrays of ints. And
in Objective-C, they're gonna be arrays of NSNumber and
in Swift, they're going to be Swift arrays of Swift Ints.
And you might ask, how is that ever gonna work?
Cuz you're talking about a struct filled with struct
versus an array class filled with these NSNumber classes.
Well the answer is, those things, array, dictionary,
then int double, and NSNumber are all bridged, magically and
automatically, okay? As you call functions that require
one to be one way or the other. It just automatically
works. Okay, there's a lot of magic going on in Objective-C
runtime to make that work. Okay, and we're gonna take
advantage of that bridging in a couple of slides here.
NSDate, brilliant important class to know about. If
you wanna put a date in your UI, you need be very careful.
Because dates are represented in a different way all over
the Earth. Date date class knows all about those ways and
it has a lot of companion classes like NSCalendar,
NSDateFormatter, NSDateComponents to help you
put dates on screen in a way that's gonna work when you
translate your app to Chinese. So NSDate is an important
class to get familiar with and understand what it can do.
Okay, if you're ever gonna put a date in your UI,
you're gonna need to know about NSDate. NSDate can also
tell you the current date and time. All right NSData,
that's a bag of bits. Okay just unstructured bag o' bits.
We use it to pass things around,
sometimes over the network like image data,
things like that. It's pretty self explanatory,
bag of bits doesn't have a lot of methods on it.
It's basically just give me the bits and here's some bits.
Okay, now let's talk about initialization, I'm gonna kind
of blast through this pretty quick. There's a really
good explanation of this in your homework in your reading
assignment. For this coming week but I'm gonna try and
give you the 50,000 foot overview of it quickly so
that you kind of have an idea what's going on as you go and
read that very detailed description, okay?
So when is an init method needed? We're talking about
initializing structs and classes okay? They're
not needed that often because of course we can say equal
something in the var. We coud use those lazy instantiation
things to get around it. Properties might be optional,
so, and they can just start off being not set.
So there's a lot of reasons you don't need an init, okay?
And frankly, most people try to design their classes and
structs so they don't need an init, okay? So you can just
create them with an init with no arguments, right,
which you get for free. Or a string in a struct case maybe
you just do what we did in demo where you just init it
with the values of all the things in the struct, okay?
So but sometimes you might find yourself needing an init
because you just can initialize things using those
mechanisms, all right? Now, you do get some free inits,
okay? We know about in classes you get the init with no
arguments for free. That's how CalculatorBrain got an init,
so we could create one. And
we also know that structs have a free
initializer to let you initialize all of the,
all of its vars. Now, One thing to know about,
[COUGH] both of those cases is that you,
if you start providing your own initializers,
then you stop getting the free one, okay?
If you provide even one initializer for your struct
you no longer get this free one, the one that does both,
okay? All right, what can you do inside of init?
What is legal to do? You can set any property's value,
even one's that already have default values.
Ones that you said equal something,
you can reset them to something else if you want.
You can set any property's value,
okay. You can even set constant properties, okay.
So if you have let something, so you have a constant in your
class, like a constant instance variable basically.
You can set that in, even though it's let,
you can set it in the initializer. Constant
properties are fairly rare. You know, why would you have
something that's constant? You might, though, you might have
something that's determined in initialization. And
then it never changes,
okay? You can call other init methods from your init,
you actually can call one other init method from n init,
okay? And you can call superclass inits, okay.
You can call your superclass initializers, but
there are rules for calling inits and they are rather
complicated. And I'm gonna go through them quick and
you're gonna read the documentations,
it's gonna give you all the details, okay? So
there are requirements inside of init, things you must do.
The previous slide was things you are allowed to do,
here's the things you must do, okay? By the time any init is
done, okay? By the time the init is finished,
all properties must have values. We know this, right?
But in Swift, all, by the time initialization is done,
all properties have to have values, and again,
optionals must have a value too, but
it could be the value not set. That's fine, okay? Now,
there are two types of init methods in a class.
Convenience methods and, convenience initializers and
designated initializers. Designated initializers
are not marked with the word convenience. Okay,
convenience initializers say convenience init whatever,
okay, in their declaration. A designated initializer must,
and can only, call a designated initializers
in it's superclass, its immediate superclass, okay?
So a designated initializer can't call a convenience
initializer in its superclass, and it can't
call a convenience super, initializers in its own class.
It must call a superclass's designated initializer. Okay,
you must initialize all the properties that you introduce
in your class, before calling a superclass's init.
Okay, so by the time you call super init to let your super
class initialize you must have all your properties
initialized, all right? You must call a superclass's init
before you can touch any of your superclass's properties.
See the order there? You do yours, call the super,
now you can touch theirs, okay? That makes sense.
You gotta let them initialize theirs before you can touch it
and you want yours initialized before they come along and
start doing their stuff. A convenience initializer must
and can only call an init, either can be user designated,
in its own class, cannot call super. Okay,
a convenience initializer cannot call super initializer.
A convenience initializer must call that in it, before it can
set any property values. It's own, or it's super classes.
Okay, in other words, it must let a designated initializer
initialize your own properties first.
And that thing is gonna call supern,
it's gonna initialize it, so by the time a convenience
intializer gets back from the emit, all the property values
will be set and it can reset them to something else,
okay. It's just a convenience. Calling other inits
has to be complete before you can access any properties.
Access I'm talking about, not set. Access any properties or
methods in yourself. So you can't say self.anything.
You know, you can't access any of the properties or
methods in yourself until you're fully initialized.
Okay, so you'll have to have called the other inits first.
Yeah? >> If you're building
an imperative class why would you
ever need convenience inits? >> So
the question is why would I ever use a convenience init?
The answer is I have a reasonable default for
some of the arguments to a designated initializer, and
it's actually possible to default things in swift.
You can basically say, equal something. But let's say you
wanna default into some calculative value, maybe based
on the other argument. A community initialize,
initializer you could create would have fewer arguments and
then turn around and call the designated one.
Okay, it's truly for convenience,
that's all these are for, phew is right, okay.
There's a lot of rules there. And it's a lot to think about.
And when you start writing your own initializers you're
gonna bump up against these all the time.
You're gonna be like I can't, I can't access that one until
I do, yeah, I gotta call supren, okay, believe me.
So try to stay away from doing your own inits,
is my advice to you. Okay, inheriting init.
Now, if you don't implement any designated inits,
you'll inherit all of your superclass's designated inits.
But if you in, if you implement even one designated
init, you don't get any of your superclass's designated
initializers, okay. If you override all of your desig,
class, superclass's designated inits, or
don't implement any of them, then you will inherit all of
the convenience initializers from your superclass, okay. In
other words, the convenience superv, initializers in your
superclass are all kinda dependent on the designated
initializer in your superclass being sensible and
making sense together. So you have to get them all
by overriding them all, or by overriding none of them. For
the convenience one to inherit,
to make, for sure make sense, okay. If you omit no inits,
you get all of your superclasses inits,
convenience and designated, okay. Any in it that
you inherit by these rules count on the previous slide.
All right, the previous slide says things like you have to,
convenience has to call a designated in your own class,
blah, blah, blah. Well, if you inherit it,
then it is in your own class. Okay, so
chew on that okay. Required init, different topic.
It is possible to mark an init with the keyword required.
That means that a subclass must implement this init.
Okay, it is not optional for it, it must.
And it can inherit if it follows these rules above.
But it must implement it, it's required, okay. UI view, for
example, which we're gonna do on Wednesday.
It has a required init.
Okay, and we're gonna see that. All right,
failable initializers, it is possible for init to fail.
We saw this double if you pass a string to the initialize,
if a double has an initializer it takes a string.
If you pass a string. That's not a double,
then it will fail, then return nil, okay.
So failable initializers cause optional versions of the thing
to be returned and you specify them with this little question
mark. You put in a question mark in there, that turns
this ititializer into the kind of initializer that will turn
an optional of this class whatever it is. Okay? And
to fail, you just return nil. Inside this initializer,
if something goes wrong, return nil, and nil will come
back to whoever's trying to get this thing. Make sense?
Okay, failable initializers are pretty rare. Images, for
example, UI image,
image named, if it can't find an image with this name,
it returns nil. Okay. So that's why this image right
here Let image. This image is an Optional UIimage. And
we probably use if-let here, if let image if we can like
this image equal to UIimage name foo, then whatever.
Okay? All right. Creating Objects All right,
usually you create an object by calling its initializer
with the appropriate arguments using the type name. So
CalculatorBrain, we've seen that,
ComplicatedObject with a bunch of arguments to create it.
Or here's let z = the type array of String initializer.
Okay, that creates an empty array of string.
It's constant, so it's gonna be empty forever, okay? But
sometimes other objects will create objects for you.
They can call a method and it will create an object for you,
give it to you, right? But
when you're creating objects from scratch, this is the.
Syntax you're using, you're used to that, right?
No questions about that, it's a kind of obvious slide. Okay,
now AnyObject, little more complicated here.
AnyObject is a special type, it's actually a protocol, but
we haven't talked about it yet, but anyway,
it's a special type. You can leave it as a type.
Protocols are types, I guess. It is used Commonly, or used,
used to be, for compatibility with Objective-C APIs,
because Objective-C, for those of you who are trying to learn
some Objective-C along the way here, Objective-C has a very
important type called ID. Okay, the type ID.
Which means pointer to a object of unknown class.
Okay. So that's a very open-ended type. [LAUGH] Okay,
Swyft doesn't do things that way. Swyft is strongly typed.
Okay, it infers types but it's strongly typed. However,
Swyft has to work with all those IOSAPIs, so
it introduced this type called AnyObject.
So AnyObject in Swyft means A point or two an object of
unknown class, okay? It only works for objects for
classes not for. So it means the same thing as objective C.
IN iOS 9 they fixed objective C. So it has almost none of
these, okay? They're still a few but very very few. So
移除了旧的实现。 但是在少数代码中还是存在的。
nowadays It is more used as an opaque type. Okay?
现在 AnyObject 主要用于需要隐藏具体细节的类型的场景。
When you want to have a point or
当你希望有一个指针指向
two in the object and you are not sure what it is or
一个对象，并且你不确定这个对象是什么你不希望让别人知道
you don't want anyone to know what it is okay?
这个对象具体是什么的时候，可以考虑用 AnyObject
So let's talk about how we can do this okay? So classes only
那么我们可以如何使用 AnyObject 这个类型呢？它只能用于 Class 类型的
and no structs. There is another type by the way. It is
对象，而不能使用在 Struct 的对象上。 这里顺带提一句， 还有另外一种类型。
what is called any, which is anything. Could be a struct,
叫做 Any， 他能指向任何类型的对象， 可以指向 Struct、
could be a class, anything. We almost, in fact, this class we
Class 以及其他所有类型的对象。 事实上，我们基本上
will never use Any, okay? You probably never wanna use it.
不会用到 Any 这个类型。 你也不会想要使用它。
It's in there, I think, for just language completeness.
它存在的意义就在于保证语法的完整性。
But I can't even think of a good explanation of why you
但是我完全无法想到你能使用到它的场景。
would wanna use it. So we're not even gonna talk about Any.
所以我们这就不讨论 Any 。
But we are gonna talk about AnyObject, okay?
我们还是继续讨论 AnyObject 吧。
So where will you see AnyObject? You'll sometimes
想想你们都在哪见过 AnyObject ？
see it in a method where one of the arguments Truly can be
你应该在在一些参数可能是多种类型的
more than one different kinds of class, mm kay? For
方法中看到它对吧？
example, you'll see on Wednesday, prepare for segue
例如将在下周三的课上才讲到的在MVC
which is a thing that prepares for transitions from one NVC
跳转前会调用 prepareForSegue 方法中含有 AnyObject 的参数。
to another, okay? We're gonna have multiple NVCs someday.
我们会在一个项目中含有非常多的 MVC 。
We're gonna wanna transition from one to the other, prepare
我们经常会从一个跳转到另一个过程，
for segue prepares for that transition. Well the sender,
而 prepareForSegue 则是为了这种跳转而存在的。 至于该方法的参数 sender，
in other words the object that initiated the transition could
换句话来说，这个对象用来初始化跳转，并且它包含
be lots of different kinds of objects.
许多不同的类型的对象。
It might be a button you collect on,
他可能是一个按钮
it might be a roll in a table, it might be some custom code
他可能是一个一个在列表中的滚动条， 它可能是一段在你的 Controller 中自定义的代码。
inside of your controller. Okay? So this sender has to be
所以这个 sender 参数必须使用 AnyObject 类型。
any object. Okay, cuz we don't know what it is. We
因为我们不知道具体情况下，它是什么？
don't know if it is a button or table row or what it is.
我们不知道它是否是一个按钮、列表或者是其他什么东西。
So AnyObject. Okay. So this is a case where he is an object,
因此最好使用 AnyObject。 这就是一个对象使用 AnyObject 的例子，
it could be many things we don't know what it is.
他可能是非常多类型的对象， 而我们不知道它具体是什么。
So we have to type this as AnyObject.
所以我们这里必须使用 AnyObject 类型。
Okay? Another example of that is touch digit. If we haven't,
另外一个例子就是之前用到的 touchDigit 方法。
when we control dragged,
如果在我们拖拽链接中，
remember when we changed it from any object to UI button,
忘记了从 AnyObject 改成 UIButton 的情况下。
Okay. If we hadn't done that, it would have created a touch
如果我们忘记了修改， 他将会创建一个 touchDigit 方法，
digit with sender AnyObject and then touch digit could've
该方法带有一个 AnyObject 类型的 sender 参数， 这样 touchDigit 方法
been sent by a UI button or maybe by UI slider. Okay. Or
可能由一个 UIButton 触发或者是 UISlider 触发。
something else. And we didn't do that because the inside
当时我们当时并没有用 AnyObject 类型的参数是因为
touch digit we wanted sender to be a UI button so
我们希望触发 touchDigit 放的的对象是 UIButton 的类型。
we just send it current title and other button things, but
这样我们就可以获得他的内容以及一些其他按钮的属性或方法，
it could have been AnyObject, all right? So, another use for
但是其实它还是可以改成 AnyObject。
AnyObject is when you wanna return essentially a cookie,
当时想要用一个密封的 Cookie 的时候， 你也可以用 AnyObject 类型。
okay? A cookie is something
Cookie 是一个
you give back where you're giving it to someone,
你给一个指定的人
they don't know what's inside of it,
但是他们不需要知道它里面的内容，
you're not gonna tell them, the only thing they can do
你也不希望告诉他们， 他们所要做的就是将它
is give it back to you, okay? So the cookie just saves some
再传递给你。 所有 Cookie 只是保存了一些
state, remembers something and you can give it back. So
状态， 或者是一些你能知道内部实现的东西。
browsers have cookies, right? You go visit a browser site,
因此浏览器有对应的 Cookie， 当你访问一个网站，
the site stores some stuff about itself and about you in
该网站会存储很多关于它的信息以及保存一些关于你信息
their cookie. When you go away and come back to that site,
的 Cookie。 当你离开这个网站的时候，这些 Cookie 会传回该网站，
it looks in the cookie and it can interpret it, okay?
如此看来的话， 该网站对 Cookie 应该是可理解的。
But it gives the cookie to the browser.
但是当将这个 Cookie 给浏览器时，
The browser has no idea what's in there. Okay.
浏览器完全无法知道它具体是什么内容。
To pick with AnyObject as far as the browser is concerned.
因此用 AnyObject 是浏览器最好的选择。
All right. So how do we use a variable type AnyObject when
那么我们如何使用一个 AnyObject 类型的对象， 并且
we don't know what the heck it is? Okay. And the answer is we
我们不知道它具体的内容？ 答案是
have to convert it to a type that we do know what it is.
我们必须将其转换成一个我们知道的类型。
Okay. Now this conversion might not be possible.
当然， 这种换换过程可能会失败，
All right, because that thing might not be of that type
因为在我们转换的过程中，
when we try to convert it. So
我们所转换的对象可能不是那种类型。
we use this as keyword in Swift to try to convert it to
因此我们在 Swift 中用一个关键字 as 尝试去
the other type. Okay. In other words, try to treat that
转换成其他类型。 也就是说， 你尝试将 AnyObject
AnyObject as something else, optionally. So this is an op,
转换成其他东西。 转换后
this returns an optional. Okay, we usually, usually use
返回的是 Optional 的类型。 我们经常用 if let 的方式
it with if let, this as thing because it ensure an optional,
因为用这个中法获得的一定是 Optaional 的类型。
right? So if I have this local variable here,
例如我这里有一个变量，
AO which is in AnyObject and I was tying it to something,
ao 是一个 AnyObject 类型， 并且我尝试将它转换成
some class I don't know what it is, okay? But I wanna try
其他类型, 并且我们不知道 ao 具体是什么类型。 但是这里我希望将其
and use AO as if it were of class SomeClass, okay,
换换成 SomeClass 这种类型。
AO might be of SomeClass, and I'm gonna see if it is, and
ao 可能是 SomeClass 这种类型， 那么如果它是的话，
if it is I'm gonna use it as some class, I say if I can let
我们将其转换成 SomeClass 并且使用它， 也就是说如果我能让 foo
foo equal AO as SomeClass, then in here there's gonna be
等于 ao 转换成 SomeClass 的对象不为空的话， 那么我这里将会等一个
a local variable foo, which is not gonna be AnyObject, it's
名为 foo 的本地变量， 并且 foo 将不再是 AnyObject 类型， 应该
gonna be of type SomeClass. Got it? Just to that symbol
是 SomeClass 类型。 明白了吗？ 使用这种方式
essentially casting if you wanna use that terminology?
将其转换成想要的类型。
Casting any object to be some class conditionally, okay?
使用 let if 这种方式将 AnyObject 转换成想要转换的类型即可。
So that's how we use something of AnyObject either that or
这就是我们如何使用 AnyObject 对象的方式， 或者是在我们
we don't know what's in there we just pass it around. Okay,
不青春它具体的内容是，而只是传递它时使用。
just pass it around to people who know what to do with it.
将其传递给真正知道它是什么内容的人。
We don't know what to do with it if it's a cookie, okay? So,
我们不知道一个 Cookie 具体能做什么。
what would code look like let's say on touchDigit.
那么如果 touchDigit 方法使用 AnyObject 参数该如何写？
If we had touchDigit and we had any object instead.
如果我们有一个 touchDigit 带有 AnyObject 的参数的话。
We probably say if we can let sendingButton equal the sender
我们可能会使用如果 sendingButton 等于 sender 转换成
as a UIbutton, then we'll treat it as a button,
UIButton 并且 sendingButton 不为空的话， 我们将其转换成，
get its currentTitle and go. Other wise else if
然后获得他的内容以及调用它的方法等。 另一方面， 如果
we can let sending slider equal to sender as UI slider,
能将其转换成 UISlider 并且不为空的话，
then we'll let the digit equal the sending sliders value
那么数字就等于 Slider 的值。
which is a double, we'll convert it to an int and
但是由于其实 Double 类型，所以我们需要将其转换成 Int
we'll convert that to a string, okay? That's how we
然后再转换成 String 类型。 这就是如何获得具体
get the digit. Did you see how we're doing kinda if let else,
数值的方式。 大家看清楚 if let 的方式
if let else? With this optional thing, that's how we
该如何操作了吗？ 这就是我们处理 AnyObject 的方式。
would use that AnyObject. All right, another use
还有一种使用 AnyOject 的场景就是
of AnyObject is Property List, okay? So Property Lists are,
用在 Property List 中。 因为 Property List 中可能包含
essentially any combination of array, dictionary, string,
数组、 字典、 字符串
double, int, NSData, and NSDate. Kay, if you build
Double、 Int、 NSData 甚至是 NSDate 类型的数据。
any data structure out of only those classes,
如果你使用这些类型来存储数据的话，
you got a property list. So it's just a word. It's just
那么你就能获得一个 Property List。 这就是我们
a term we use to mean that. Kay, that's what it means.
想要的类型。 这就是它的含义。
And you might feel like, wait a second. Array,
等等，或许你会想：
AnyObject has to be a class, it cannot be a structs.
AnyObject 是一个Class类型， 而不是 Struct 类型。
But string, array, dictionary, double, those are structs.
但是 String、 Array、 Dictionary、 Double 这些都是 Struct 类型。
So how could this ever be in a property list. How could it
那么他们如何包含在一个 Property List 中呢？
ever be any object. And the answer is the bridging, kay?
他们是如何转换成 AnyObject 类型呢？ 答案是桥接。
We got this automatic bridging to Objective-C, kay?
它们能自动转换成Objective C。
It automatically treats them like NSDictionary, NSArray,
它们会自动转换成 NSDictionary、 NSArray、
NSNumber, which are all classes. And allows them to be
NSNumber 或者是任何它们的封装类型。 这样就允许他们转换成 AnyObject了。
AnyObject, kay? Now these property lists
那么通过这种方式
are passed around blindly. The people who are looking in them
Property List 就在传递过程中可以不让人知道具体内容。 那么及时有人破解它的话，
are only knowing that their dictionaries and
他们也只能知道字典、数组
arrays of strings and dates and stuff.
字符串、日期以及一些其他的东西。
They don't know anything about what that data means, okay.
但是他们却不知道具体数据的含义。
They're just being passed around, so
那么它就可以被传递了。
let's look at an API and iOS that uses a property
那么让我们看看 iOS 中的一个 API， 一个便于
list to understand it better. It's called NSUserDefaults.
我们理解 Property List 的API。 那就是 NSUserDefaults。
What NSUserDefaults does, is it takes a property list and
那么 NSUserDefaults 是拿来干嘛的呢？ 它是用来缓存 Property List
makes it persistent on disk. So when your app quits and
并且将其保存到磁盘上的。 那么当你 App 退出重启后，
runs again and you look it up again, it's there.
你能从新查询到保存的数据， 因为它保存在磁盘了。
So it's basically a database of property lists,
它有点类似一个 Property List 的基础数据库，
a database of structures with dictionaries, arrays, dates,
一个包含字典，数组，日期的数据库。
okay, that's what it is.
这就是N SUserDefaults。
It's a small database so don't use it for big things.
由于它是一个微型数据库，所以我们一般用它来保存大的数据。
You wouldn't wanna store like a dictionary of the entire
例如你绝对不会想用它来保存
English language in there. It's for
所以英语的字典。
small things like settings and things like that. The API on
他只是用来存一些小东西，例如设置、配置等一些小的东西。
it is very simply just say, setObject, property list here,
并且它的接口也非常简单， 只需要调用 setObject 用来存 Property List,
forKey, string. And then you can look it up and
用 String 来存 Key。 这样你就可以通过
get the property list back. So here you can see how you're
get 方法重新获得具体的 Property List。 你可以看得出，这里你
just passing it around. You're storing it as a cookie and
只是负责传递给NSUserDefaults。 你想保存 Cookie 一样保存它，
it's user defaults has no idea what's inside there.
并且 NSUserDefaults 对于里面具体是什么完全不了解。
It just knows it's only array is dictionary strings,
它只知道他可能是数组、 字典、 字符串
ints, etc, okay. It can also restore smaller things.
数值等一些数据。 并且能通过它重新获得这些小数据。
Like as I said a double, and it will make a little property
例如我告诉它保存一个 Double， 那么他就会创建一个小的 Property List
list out of a double because a double by itself Is a property
用来保存 Double， 因为 Double 会是一个 Property List 类型。
list, right? Because it's one of those classes, okay?
它是一个 Class 的类型。
Just like array is. How do you use user defaults?
就像一个数组一样。 那么你是如何使用 NSUserDefaults 的呢？
You create a shared one using this class or type method,
你只需调用它的类方法，
NSUserDefaults.standardUserDe- faults().
一个叫 NSUserDefaults.standardUserDefaults() 的方法。
This gives you the shared instance of standard, of user
这个方法将会返回一个共享的 NSUserDefaults 对象。
defaults. And then you just say To it. Get me a certain
接下来你只需调用它的方法获得数据，或者
property list, write this property list out. The changes
将一些数据写入即可。
you make will automatically be saved eventually, but
这些改变将会自动的保存下来，
if you wanna force them to be saved on disk, you can do
但是如果你想强制将其保存到磁盘的话， 你可以调用
synchronize, which returns a bool, which we almost always
synchronize 这个方法， 这个方法返回一个布尔类型，
ignore because not clear what to do if it fails.
这个返回值经常被我们忽略， 因为我们并不清楚它做什么，并且是否失败。
It would probably only fail if your disk were full.
如果返回时的false的话， 则表示你的磁盘以满。
Not sure what you're gonna do at that point, but any way.
并且你不确定如果失败了你应该做什么。
We usually ignore that return value, okay? Another example
我们经常会忽略这个返回值。
of property list might be in our calculator brain and
另一个使用 Property List 的例子将会在我们的 CalculatorBrain中使用，
I'm gonna show you a demo of this.
我将会在接下来的Demo进行展示。
Really quick here, which is, what if we wanted to get
接下来会讲非常快，关于假如我们希望在计算器中
the program that it's in the calculator? Right now,
获得它之前的运算结果。
our calculator could be programmed by saying
现在的计算能可以计算出类似：
five times four times three equals, let's put a program
5 乘以 4 乘以 3 等于什么这种运算， 我们只需将具体
in the calculator, right? Five times four times three.
操作输入计算器中即可。 输入 5 * 4 * 3.
It's kinda simple program. It'd be cool if we get
这个是非常简单的运算， 那么如果计算器能
that program and the person who got it,
将这种与运算表达式交给一个完全
it doesn't know anything about our internal data structure.
不了解运算表达式内部实现的人，那肯定非常溜的功能。
So it's AnyObject to them. And then later,
那么这就可以用上 AnyObject了。
they could come back to the CalculatorBrain and
只需将重新传递运算表达式给 CalculatorBrain，
say. Run this program that you gave me earlier, you see? So
并且告诉它， 运行这些你之前给我的运算表达式， 这样就可以得到答案了。
we use AnyObject as kind of this opaque program.
因此我们在这里用 AnyObject 来代表一个不透明的运算表达式。
Okay. Now this doesn't seem very variable right now.
不过现在看起来好像不可以带参数的。
But it's gonna be really valuable in assignment two,
但是我们希望将其做成可带参数的，
when you're gonna add variables to your calculator.
之后只需将参数的具体值告诉给你的计算器即可。
You're gonna be able to say three times X times five
也许你希望保存表达式 3 * X * 5这种表达式，
equals, where X is a variable, and
其中 X 是一个变量，
then you can run this then you get this program using this
那么你可以使用我接下来
code I'm going to show you here, the property list, and
将要完成的代码， 并且在代码中使用 Property List，这样你
then later you can, they can set the variable x and
可以做到了， 你可以设置变量 X 的值，并且重新运行
run it again. Maybe set the x to something else and
具体的表达式。 可以设置 X 为任意的一个值，然后
run the program again and again and again, you see?
不断的重复运行这个表达式。
So this would be a good use of AnyObject, because
那么希望这样的话， 最好使用 AnyObject 类型，
the calculator brain doesn't wanna give away its internal
因为 CalculatorBrain 并不想泄露
data struc for how, structure for how it represents
他的类型以及它是如何
a program. But it's happy to let someone have the program
重新运算该表达式的。  但是可以让别人拥有该运算表达式，
and give it to them later and they'll run again it later.
并且将其重新交给计算器， 计算器将会重新计算该运算表达式。
Make sense, see why we want it?
这样就可以理解为什么使用 AnyObject 了吧？
Now why would we make it a property list?
那么我们这里为什么要用使用 Property List 呢？
Because it'd be nice to store it in user defaults, right?
因为这样方面将其存入到 NSUserDefaults 里。
I've got a program? I'm gonna put it in the user defaults.
当我获得一个表达式之后， 我将其保存在 NSUserDefaults 中。
Next time my program runs, I can pull it out and
当下次我的程序运行时， 我能从 NSUserDefaults 重新获得，
ask a calculator brain to run it. You see,
然后让 CalculatorBrain 重新运算它。
it's just more flexible to be a property list.
由此可以看出 Property List 相对比较灵活。
So that's what we're gonna do. We're gonna create a var
我们接下来就按照上面的方法来实现。 首先，我们在 CalculatorBrain 中先创建一个
called program in our calculator brain.
叫做 program 的的属性。
It's gonna be gettable and settable. When you get it,
并且给他添加 get 和 set 的方法。 当你获得它的值得时候，
it gets the current program in, that the calculator brain
他将会给出之前当前表达式， 之前计算过的表达式。
has just run, and if you set it, it runs the program, okay?
当时你设置它的值得时候， 该表达式会重新运算一遍。
All right, so I'm gonna do that as the demo. I'm gonna
好的，接下来我讲在我们的Demo上添加该功能。
finish off the slides here first. One thing about this
不过我们先讲完所有的幻灯片。 首先是关于强制转换的，
casting, you can cast other things besides any object,
你可以强制转换任何类型，而不单单是 AnyObject。
okay. So you, for example, you can look at this slide later,
例如像幻灯片上所展示的，
but you could have a class that's a subclass of another
当你有一个子类的对象指向父类的指针的情况下，
class, okay? And you can try and cast using as to get
你可以将父类指针强制转换成子类的对象。
the subclass. You're not sure whether it's a subclass, but
虽然你没办法确定它是否是子类的对象，
you can cast and as will tell you whether it is, okay?
但是你可以通过强制转换的结果告诉你是否是其子类。
In this case, for example, if I have view controller
例如，我有一个UIViewController的变量，
the base class of our view controller, we can't say
但是我们没办法使用
vc.displayValue cuz this is a CalculatorViewController
vc.displayValue, 因为这个属性是属于 CalculatorViewController 的属性。
thing. But if I went and as'ed it, okay,
当时如果我进行强制转换的话，
if I took this VC and as'ed it to CalculatorViewController,
我将其强制转换成 CalculatorViewController 后，
now I could use displayValue. Okay, so as is for
我就可以使用 displayValue 这个属性了。 因此强制转换
more than just any object.
不单单是针对 AnyObject。
Okay, and yes, you can force with as!,
当然你也可以使用关键字 as! 来进行强制转换，
it'll crash if it can't do it. Assertions I'm not gonna talk
但是如果没办法进行强制转换的话， 你的程序会崩溃。 我不会在这里进行
about cuz we talked about it in the debugging section.
讲解断言， 因为我们将在调试的章节进行讲解。
You can look at the slide or the reading assignment to find
你可以查看幻灯片或者是阅读作业来查看
out more about assert. And that's it. So coming up on
更多的关于断言的信息。 记得周三来听
Wednesday I'm gonna start talking about custom drawing.
关于自定义绘制的课程。
On Friday we don't have a section for this week.
这周五， 我们没有课程。
And next Monday I'm gonna start talking about gestures,
下周我们我们开始讲解手势，
multi-touch gestures, okay, pinches and swipes and
多点触摸手势， 缩放以及滑动手势等，
stuff leading up to your assignment three,
并且该内容将会在你的第三次作业中用到，
which is you're gonna be doing a lot of drawing and
第三次作业包含了绘制、 多 MVC 以及其他的一些内容。
multiple MVCs and all that stuff. Your assignment this
这周的作业是
week is going to be the variables thing, okay?
关于变量的题目。
All right, so let's do that program var, okay?
接下来我们开始实现 program 属性吧。
Just gonna go back to our calculator here, all right,
重新回到计算器的程序，
and leave off exactly where we were. All right,
回到我们之前结束的地方。
so here's my controller, right here.
屏幕上显示的是我的 Controller。
I'm not gonna change my controller to do this.
目前我还不打算修改 Controller。
This is purely a brain thing, okay, here's my brain,
所需修改的都在 CalculatorBrain 中，
calculator brain. So I'm gonna add a new var.
这就是我的 CalculatorBrain 的代码， 我讲为其添加一个新的属性。
Let's put it I don't know, down here, okay?
我们加在那呢？ 就这里吧。
It's gonna be called program. It's AnyObject.
取名为 program， 类型为 AnyObject。
Now I'm gonna make it be AnyObject, but I'm also gonna
这里虽然我给他的类型为 AnyObject， 但是我同事也可以给他的类型
make it be a property list, cuz it's more useful.
为 PropertyList， 因为这个名字更加有可读性。
People can put it in as user defaults or whatever.
其他人可以将其存在 NSUserDefaults 或者是其他的地方。
So I'm gonna use a cool Swift thing called typealias.
这里就要用到一个 Swift 的一个特性， 叫做 typealias 。
typealias lets you create a type, a name type,
typealias 让你可以创建一个新的类型， 一个别名的类型，
that's exactly the same as some other type. So
它实际上与你绑定的类型是等价的。
I'm gonna create a type called PropertyList which equals
这里我讲创建一个叫做 PropertyList 的类型，并且它与
AnyObject. So PropertyList is now a type in Swift.
AnyObject 等价。 那么这样之后， PropertyList 就是一个新的类型了。
It's exactly the same thing as AnyObject.
但是其实他是跟 AnyObject 等价的。
Now why would I create this? That's because
为什么我要创建这个类型呢？
I'm gonna change this to say PropertyList. So
因为我希望这里的类型名称是 PropertyList。
I'm gonna cha, make the type of my program be PropertyList.
然后将 program 的类型修改成新的类型 PropertyList。
This tells anyone using my program that yeah,
这就等于告诉任何用 program 属性的人，
it's AnyObject but it's also a PropertyList, okay?
虽然他是一个 AnyObject 类型，但是它同样是 PropertyList 类型。
This is documentation. I'm essentially documenting here
这就是文档化， 我本来就是进行文档化
that this AnyObject is PropertyList.
即 AnyObject 改名为 PropertyList。
I could have also just put some comments in my code that
并且我也会将在代码中添加对应的注释
says it is, but this kind of really hammers home the po,
这是一个非常好的做法将 program 的
the point here that this is a PropertyList,
类型修改成 PropertyList。
okay? Now I'm gonna have my program here be computed,
现在我将要把我的运算表达式拿来计算。
okay? So I'm gonna do the get set thing, right? And
因此我要添加 get 和 set 方法。
so now I need to have my program internally,
因此我需要有一个内部的变量用来存储运算表达式，
I mean, internally store my program, so I'm actually gonna
我的意思是在该类中存储运算表达式的变量，
go up to the top and create another private var
因此我们回到程序的上端，添加一个新的私有属性
which is my internalProgram. And
名叫 internalProgram 的属性。
so I have to think about how I'm gonna store my program,
因此我需要考虑我应该如何存储我的运算表达式，
you know, all the operands and operations, internally. And
而我们知道所有的运算表达式都是有操作数和操作符组成的。
I'm just gonna store it to show you the power of
因此我只需要存储这些信息，并且用来展示 AnyObject 的强大。
AnyObject. I'm gonna store it as an array of AnyObject,
因此我这里用一个 AnyObject 的数组来存储这些信息。
okay? And the objects in that array are gonna be a double if
而数组中的元素可能是 Double 类型，当然是一个操作数的时候，
it's an operand or a string if it's an operation. So
可能是一个 String 类型，当它是一个操作符的时候。
I'm gonna have an array that has a mix of doubles and
因此我这里需要一个混合了 Double 和 String 类型的数组，
strings, okay, and that's gonna store my program.
用来存储的运算表达式。
I'm just gonna put operands in as doubles and I'm gonna put
我只需将操作数以 Double 的形式进行存储，
operations as strings. So that's another power of
将操作符以 String 的形式进行存储。 这里就能展示 AnyObject 的优势之一了。
AnyObject here. So how do I implement my internalProgram?
那么我应该如何使用 internalProgram 呢？
Real simple, okay. When I set an operand, I'm just gonna
非常简单， 当我调用 setOperand 的时候，
tell my internalProgram append that operand, oops.
我只需将对应的操作数添加到 internalProgram 中即可。
Okay, now normally this is AnyObject.
当时这里使用的是 AnyObject 类型做为数组元素的类型，
Operand is a double, that's a struct. That normally wouldn't
但是操作数是一个 Double 的类型， 它是一个Struct。 原本应该是没办法
work, but the bridging, the Objective-C bridging,
存入数组中的， 但是苹果的桥接技术做到了， 就是与 Objective-C 的桥接技术
will make this work. Okay, I told you everywhere in the UI
使的操作数能存入数组中。 我之前在讲 UI 的时候也提到过，
where you have this compatibility,
Swift 与 Objective-C 是具有非常好的兼容性。
it's gonna automatically bridge.
因为苹果内部已经实现了自动的桥接技术。
I don't, look, I don't have to do anything or say anything.
而我不需要做任何事情。
It just automatically always bridges when necessary.
当它需要兼容的时候，就会自动进行桥接。
Okay, similar down here in my operation.
当然，下面的操作符也是同样的处理方式。
When someone performs an operation, I'm just gonna tell
当有人调用 performOperation 时， 我只需将它加到
my internalProgram append the symbol for this operation.
运算表达式的 internalProgram 变量即可。
Okay, that's a string. Again, a struct but
但是操作符是一个 String， 同样是一个 Struct 类型，
it's automatically bridged to NSString and
但是它会自动使用桥接技术， 转换成 NSString 类型，
thus can be an AnyObject. Okay, that's it, that's
所能能将其转换成 AnyObject 类型。
the entire implementation of my internalProgram.
这就是关于所有的 internalProgram 属性的使用。
I'm just remembering every operand and operation.
我只需记住没有一个操作数和操作符即可。
So now I'm just gonna return that internalProgram here,
接着在这里我只需返回 internalProgram 即可，
okay, to be the program.
用来返回 prgram。
Now you might be freaking out, whoa, you're returning
也许你会吓到， 为什么你这里
your internal data structure here to a public caller. But
要讲私有的数据返回给公用的接口？
what kind of type is an array? A value type. And
但是数组具体是什么类型？ 是一个值传递的类型。
what happens when you return a value type? It gets copied.
那么一个值传递类型的数据作为返回值会出现什么情况？ 会用它的副本进行返回。
Okay, so I'm not returning a pointer to my internal data
因此我不是返回一个指向内部数据的指针对象，
structure here, I'm returning a copy. Okay, that's, again,
而是返回它的一个副本而已。
a cool thing about having these things be value types.
由此可以看出一个值传递类型的优点。
All right, so now we have to do the set. So someone can now
那么解析来我们实现一下 set 方法。 目前别人能获得
get my program and they can give it back to me later and
我的运算表达式， 并且之后会将其重新交给我，
I have to run it. Okay, so how am I gonna do that?
而我必须重新运算一遍这个表达式。 那么我该如何实现呢？
Well, when someone sets my program, first I'm gonna clear
首先，当有人需要重新给我运算表达式的时候， 我先要清空
whatever's in my program. So you, you guys probably
当前的运算表达式。 而在之后的作业中，
implemented something like this for your homework, but
也可能会遇到类似的题目。
I'm gonna, see clear my accumulator. I'm gonna say
而这里我需要重置操作数， 将
that I have no pending binary operation. And I'm gonna
pending 属性有置为空并且
clear my internalProgram that I currently have out.
将当前存储的操作数和操作符都清空。
Actually I'll just removeAll items from my internalProgram.
事实上我只需将数组中的所有元素移除即可。
Okay, so that's clear cuz I'm running a new program, so
这就是我的清空方法， 然后我需要重新运算新的运算表达式，
I wanna clear all my stuff out.
但是在此之前我必须重置我的所有属性。
Right, make sense? Now I'm just gonna say if
而我现在只需判断
the program they get me, gave me is an array of op,
他们给我的新的运算表达式是否是一个操作数和操作符的数组，
operands and operations, so I'm gonna
而我这里只需要
say if I can let arrayOfOps equal this newValue that they
通过 if let arrayOfOps = newValue as? [AnyObject]
just gave me as an array of AnyObject, which it has to be.
的语句进行判断，并且该判断必须要成立。
If it's not that, I can just ignore this. Someone gave
如果它不成立的话，我就直接忽视它即可。
me a program which was not one that I gave out, so I'm
例如有人给了一个运算表达式给我， 但是却不是从我这里给出的，
ignoring it, cuz it's gotta be an array of AnyObject or
那么我讲忽视它， 因此它必须是一个 AnyObject 的数组，
I can't figure out what it is. So if it is, now I'm just
否则我无法判断里面具体是什么内容。 那么如果它是一个数组的话，
gonna go look through at all the ops in there,
我只需遍历所有在数组中
all the operations and operands. Okay, an arrayOfOps.
的操作数和操作符。
Okay, that's how we loop through an array, right, for
这就是我们常用的遍历数组的方式———— for in 的方式。
in. And for each one I'm gonna check and see what it is.
对于每一个元素我都进行检查看看它是什么。
Now what type, if I can Alt-click on this,
那么这里的 op 是什么类型呢？ 如果我通过 Alt + 左键点击op的话，
what type is this gonna be? >> AnyObject?
会显示什么类型呢？ [学生回答] AnyObject ?
>> AnyObject, exactly.
对的， 就是 AnyObject 类型。
See, AnyObject. So I can't do anything with AnyObject,
看见没， 就是 AnyObject 类型。 但是我们还没办法处理 AnyObject 类型，
so I have to try and see if I can make it something else.
因此我必须尝试看看能否做一些其他的事情。
So I'm gonna first try and make it be an operand by
首先我先进行判断它是否是一个 Double 类型的
saying op as a Double, okay? So if I get to here,
操作数？ 如果运行到这一行的话，
then this op,
那么这个 op 在数组中的变量
the next thing I looked in the array was a Double. Excellent,
就是一个 Double 类型的数据。
then I can just say setOperand to be that operand, okay,
那么接下来我就可以调用  setOperand 来进行进行处理这个操作数。
cuz I'm running the program. So I'm just gonna replay,
因为我这里是重新运行运算表达式， 所以我这里只需对
basically, my operands and operations. Otherwise,
操作数和操作符进行一遍运算。
if I can let, let's say operation = op as a String,
另一方面， 我通过 let operation = op as? String 来进行判断是否是操作数，
okay, then I'm going to perform that operation.
如果是操作数的话， 这里就调用一下 performOperation 的方法。
Okay? Done, okay, very simple, I've done it.
实现好了，非常简单吧。
Now you're going to have to really make sure you
那么目前你必须保证你是理解
understand this, because you need to enhance this for your
这些代码的， 因为你需要对该项目进行完善， 在作业中
assignment number two. Because you're gonna have variables,
用到类似的方法。 例如你将用到变量，
you're gonna have to deal with here too. You're gonna have
而你也需要处理这些变量。
variables in your program, not just operands and operations.
你需要处理的你的运算表达式， 而不是仅仅的操作数与操作符。
Now, let's see this thing in action.
那么看我们来实际运行看看。
We've got this code and we wanna make sure it works, so
我们写好了这些代码，我们需要确认是否它实现成功了，
let's put something in our UI that actually checks
我们需要在界面上添加一些东西来检查这段
this program business.
程序的正确性。
So, I'm gonna go back to my storyboard.
所以我们先回到我们的 Storyboard。
I'm gonna steal a couple of buttons here. I'm gonna make
我这里只需要修改一些按钮。
this be the save button and this be the restore button.
将这个按钮变成保存的按钮， 而下面一个按钮变成重新运算的按钮。
So I'm gonna have the save button, save the program, and
而保存的按钮用来保存之前的运算表达式，
then I have the restore button, restore the program.
重新运算的按钮用来重新运算之前的的运算表达式。
Okay, so you can see how it would look like to use that.
这样你就可以想象我们应该如何使用它了。
So these are not operation buttons anymore, so
而这两个按钮不在是操作符的按钮，
I'm gonna disconnect using right-click,
所以我需要通过右键来断开之前链接的事件，
all these perform operations. Okay,
所有这两个按钮的事件回调。
then I'm gonna wire these up. Let's make some room. Wire up,
解析来我要重新绑定事件的回调。 让我们让 Xcode 多一些控件来进行绑定。
down here. All right, so I'm gonna wire up save first.
那么我们先对保存按钮进行绑定事件的回调方法。
Put it right here. I'll call it save. It's an action.
将其拖拉到这里， 并且给方法取名为 save, 设置它是 Action。
It doesn't need an arg,
该方法不需要参数，
I don't need the sender this time, this is the first time
这次回调方法不需要一个参数， 这是我们第一次遇到不需要
we've seen where we don't need the sender. Okay,
参数的回调方法。
at least the first time not in your homework.
至少不是在你的作业中的第一次遇到。
And here's restore. And restore is also an action, and
同样的方法拉一个 restore 的事件回调， 同样是一个 Action，
it doesn't need an argument either. Here we go, there's
同样不需要一个参数。 这样就可以了，
save and restore. Okay, how am I gonna implement this? Well,
这就是我们的两个按钮的事件回调的方法。 那么我具体该如何实现呢？
I need the saved program, so I'm gonna have a savedProgram.
我需要保存之前的运算表达式， 所以我需要一个 saveProgram 的属性。
Its type could be any object, but
它的类型可以是 AnyObject， 但是
I'm actually gonna have it be CalculatorBrain.PropertyList.
这里更建议使用 CalculatorBrain.PropertyList 的类型。
Just to be clear to myself, this is a property list, and
首先你的自己清楚， 这是一个 PropertyList，
if I wanted to save this into NFC or default,
并且如果我我想将其存入 NSUserDefaults 的话，
I could. Okay, but I'm not going to, but I could.
我也能做到。  但是目前我还没算这样做， 即使我是能做到的。
All right, so how do I save?
那么我该如何实现 save 方法呢？
And I'm gonna make this optional because,
在此之前我应该将其变成一个 Optional 的类型，
of course I might not have hit save yet.
因为我刚开始可能没有保存过预算表达式。
So it's gonna start out as nil,
那么它的初始值应该是 nil .
as soon as I hit save it's gonna have a value. All right,
直到我触发 save 方法之后， 它才会有值。
so how do I save? Well, I'm just gonna say that this
那么我们该如何实现 save 方法呢？ 我应该
savedProgram = the calculators brain.program.
将 CalculatorBrain 中的 program 保存到 savedProgram 即可。
Okay, that's gonna store it in there, really good, you see?
只需在这里保存即可， 非常简单， 对吧？
How about restore? Okay, well, if I have a savedProgram
那么 restore 方法又该如何实现呢？ 如果 savedProgram 不为
!= nil, then I'm just gonna set the brains.program
空的话， 我将其重新传递给 CalculatorBrain。
= savedProgram. Okay, I have to unwrap it,
并且我这里需要强制解析它，
cuz it's an optional. And then I'd better update my display
因为他是一个 Optional 的类型。 然后我需要更新我
value now because the brain is gonna have a different result.
显示的值， 因为 CalculatorBrain 可能重新运算后会有不同的结果。
It's got a new program, it's gonna have a different result,
因为它获得了一个新的运算表达式， 所以它可能会运算跟当前显示不同的结果。
got it? Okay now, this code,
看明白这段代码了吗？
you don't need this in your assignment. This is,
这些代码应该在作业中用不到。
I'm only putting this here just to demonstrate program.
这只是我放在这里的实例代码而已。
You will need the other code in CalculatorBrain,
你需要在 CalculatorBrain 中的其他代码，
but you will not need this code. Okay, let's go ahead and
而不需要这段代码。 那么让我重新
run this. All right,
运行这个程序。
here we go, make this a little bigger. All right,
将模拟器变大一点。
let's rotate so that our restore button looks better.
将模拟器进行旋转一下， 这样我们的 restore 按钮看起来更美观一点。
All right, here we go. So let's put a program in here,
我们先输入一个表达式，
4 x 5 + 1 =. Okay, that's 21. Okay, let's save that program,
输入 4 乘以 5 加上 1 等于。 答案是21. 然后点击保存按钮。
now let's do pi square root. Okay, that's good, + 8 =,
然后在点击π、 根号、 加号、 8 等一些其他按钮。
something like that. Now let's restore. What should happen to
然后点击 restore 按钮， 那么会发生什么呢？
our display when I restore? >> 21.
如果我点击 restore 后。 [学生回答] 21.
>> 21 cuz it's gonna rerun
答案是21， 因为我们重新运算了之前的
that program. And sure enough, there it is.
运算表达式。 这个是可以肯定的。
Okay, 14 divided by 7=, restore. Okay, we, we,
14 除以 7 等于， 点击restore。 看见没？
we've run that program, and that's the result in there, so
我们重新运算了之前的表达式， 所以它的结果就展示在这里了。
we can say x 2 =. Okay, we could save
而我们可以针对结果继续运算， 如乘以 2 等于之类的。
it again. Okay, 47 divide 8 =, and now when we restore,
当然我们重新保存新的表达式。 继续输入 47 除以 8 等于， 然后我们在点击 restore 按钮，
we'll get 42, which is the meaning of life, the universe,
我们还是能拿到 42，也就是说无论从哪个角度来
and everything, and so we're done, okay. So
说， 我们都完成了想要的功能。
get that program to code into your app, okay.
将这部分代码拷贝到你们的程序中，
You'll need to add that to your assignment one, and then
你将会在作业一种需要用到这些代码，
I will be publishing, I might actually publish assignment
当然我会将这些代码发布出来， 我也会将作业二
two before Wednesday, okay. It goes out on Wednesday,
在周三前发布出来。 作业将在周三发布，
due the next Wednesday. But for those of you who want to
直到下周三为止。 当然对于那些想先多学一点
start a little early, cuz you know everything you need to
的同学们， 因为已经学会了一些
know now to do assignment two as well, okay. So
你们也可以提前做作业二。
I'll probably publish that earlier, maybe tomorrow.
我会尽早将其发布出来，也可能是明天。
>> For more,
想获得更多信息，
please visit us at stanford.edu.
请访问我们的网站 stanford.edu。